大侦探波洛探案集
1935年好莱坞电影《执法铁汉》('G' Men) 詹姆斯·卡格尼主演
啊
Aah!
放开我  放开我
Let me go! Let me go!
詹姆斯·贾普总督察
Chief Insp. James Japp
伦敦警察厅警察
第二季第7集
廉价公寓房历险记
亚瑟·黑斯廷斯上尉
Captain Arthur Hastings
波洛的好友与忠诚助手
赫尔克里·波洛
Hercule Poirot
著名侦探 比利时人
来啊 警探
Come on, copper!
你想让她吃枪子儿吗?
Are you gonna let her have it?!
来啊
Come on!
来啊 警探 出来受死吧
Come on, copper! Come on out and get it!
放开我
Let go!
啊
Aaaah!
谢 谢 观 赏
结束了 波洛 你可以把眼睛睁开了
It's all over, Poirot. You can open your eyes now.
黑斯廷斯 这是最后一次
Hastings, this is the last time.
给我老实点
You behave yourself!
不要发出那种怪声音
Stop that noise!
快走 快走
Go on. Off you go.
你也许不喜欢 但你必须承认
You might not like it, Poirot, but you can't ignore it.
它是我们生活中的一部分 是世界的一扇窗
It's part of our lives. A window on the world.
野蛮人
Barbaric.
我不喜欢这种类型的罪犯
I care not for this type of criminal,
或是那些美国侦探们
nor for the detectives of the United States
他们总是先开枪再问问题
who shoot first and ask the questions later.
啊 算了吧 波洛
Aw, come on, Poirot.
也不全是枪战和黑帮歹徒
It's not all machine guns and mobsters.
事实上 要说调查犯罪的能力
In fact, when it comes to criminal investigation,
联邦调查局是首屈一指的
the FBI are second to none.
哦 当然仅次于伦敦警察厅
Well, except for Scotland Yard, of course.
是的 不久后我就会让你知道
Yes, well, I'll let you know soon enough
他们到底是不是名副其实
if they live up to their reputation.
为了侦破一个案子
They're sending us one of their agents over
他们派来了一名探员
on temporary assignment.
上帝啊
Mon Dieu.
这是不是意味着美国的黑帮歹徒
Does that mean that the gangsters of America
准备潜入伦敦的大街小巷了?
are preparing to stalk the streets of London?
别怕
No fear.
是一起间谍案件
No, it's a spy case of some kind.
他跟着某条线索一直到这儿
He's following up a lead over here,
我要和他一起办案
and I've got to work with him.
我希望他别像电影里的主人公那样
I hope he does not take after his film counterpart,
那个"砖头"戴维斯
M. Brick Davis.
至于我嘛 今晚你朋友帕克先生举办的聚会
For me, the party tonight of your friend M. Parker
带给我的刺激刚刚好
will be excitement enough.
肯定不是这个地方
This can't be the place, surely.
他们一定是写错了
There must have been some kind of mistake.
"坎普登山门公寓"
"Campden Hill Gate."
一年只要八十英镑 也许只是在转租茶水间吧
Well, for £80 a year, they must be subletting the boiler room.
詹姆士·罗宾逊
James Robinson
租到廉价公寓的年轻丈夫
斯特拉·罗宾逊太太
Mrs. Stella Robinson
租到廉价公寓的年轻妻子
"五房公寓 设施齐全 装修现代化"
"Five-room flat with all modern conveniences."
二楼6室
Number 6 is on the first floor.
快点 詹姆士
Come on, James.
让我猜猜 你们要租6室那户便宜的房子
Don't tell me. Number 6 -- the cheap flat.
别浪费时间了 亲爱的 已经租出去了
Don't waste your time, dear. It's been let.
而且他们非常粗鲁
And rude.
我刚报上名字
The moment I uttered my name,
他们就把门甩上了
they slammed the door in my face.
斯特拉
Stella.
也许他们只是不喜欢她的样子
Perhaps they just didn't like the look of her.
晚上好
Good evening.
- 我们得知--  - 姓名?
-We understand -- -Name?
罗宾逊 罗宾逊先生和太太
Robinson. Mr. and Mrs. Robinson.
- 我们来是--  - 啊
-We were hop-- -Ah.
谢谢
Thank you.
就像冰块融化一样
It was like a melting frost.
她微笑着把我们请进屋 带我们参观了那套公寓
All smiles, she ushered us in, and we were shown over the flat.
那房子真是太棒了 我们马上就会搬过去
Which was terrific. We're moving in right away.
也许房子闹鬼吧 里面曾经发生过惨案
Well, perhaps it's haunted, the scene of a grisly murder.
哦 别这么说
Oh, don't.
以那样的价格 她倒是能吓跑鬼怪
At that price, she can haunt away.
我们的侦探朋友怎么看?
How about our detective friends?
泰迪·帕克
Teddy Parker
黑斯廷斯的老朋友
波洛先生 您是专家 您怎么看?
M. Poirot, you're the expert. What do you think?
先生
Sir?
真不巧 我并不是鬼怪方面的专家
Unfortunately, in the matter of ghosts, I am no expert.
太太
Madam?
但你们看 有两件事很奇怪
But there are two things which are odd, you see.
那则招租广告登了有一阵子了
The flat had been advertised for some time.
房租如此低廉 这么久都没租出去确实很奇怪
Well, strange when you consider how low the rent was.
这么说 你们之前见过那则广告
Well, you'd seen the advertisement before
但并没有理会
and didn't bother with it.
我们原以为是场骗局
We thought it was a hoax.
我们最终仅是出于好奇才去的
Eventually we only went out of curiosity.
正好它离我们的住处也不远
We thought, as we were in the area --
对极了
Precisely.
其他人看了广告也会这么想
That's just what everyone else thought.
但为什么比我们先一步到的
But why was that other woman turned away
那个女士会被拒绝?
just before we called,
而我们却得到热情的欢迎?
and yet we were welcomed with open arms?
啊 是啊
Aha. Yes.
嘿 亚瑟 这一点你怎么解释?
Oh, come on, Arthur. How do you get out of that one?
这很明显啊 不是吗?
Well, it's obvious, isn't it?
她一定是走错房间了
She must have gone to the wrong flat.
你们看 黑斯廷斯上尉可以解答一切谜团
You see, Captain Hastings can explain every mystery.
费利西蒂·莱蒙小姐
Miss Felicity Lemon
波洛的秘书
谢谢 莱蒙小姐
Thank you, Miss Lemon.
- 早安 波洛  - 早安
-Morning, Poirot. -Good morning.
早安 莱蒙小姐
Morning, Miss Lemon.
波洛先生刚给我讲了昨晚你在泰迪·帕克家
Mr. Poirot's been telling me about your skillful deductions
聚会上做的精彩推理
at Teddy Parker's party last night.
你应该知道 波洛 我有时候觉得
You know, Poirot, I sometimes think
适当的时候你应该承认我的能力
you don't give me credit where it's due.
我知道一切谜题在你看来都是小儿科
I know it all seemed rather simplistic to you,
但我那是故意说得圆滑些罢了
but I was merely being tactful.
- 圆滑?  - 答案很明显 不是吗?
-Tactful? -Well, it's obvious, isn't it?
罗宾逊夫妇一定漏看了合同中的某些条目
The Robinsons have overlooked something in their agreement.
他们很快就会发现的
They'll find out what it is soon enough.
我只是希望那些条目别太吓人
I just hope it doesn't come as too much of a shock.
我明白了
I see.
黑斯廷斯 我很高兴你对罗宾逊夫妇
Well, Hastings, I'm glad that you show concern
遇到的问题甚是关心
for the problem of the Robinsons.
这会让我们的调查更有价值的
It will make our inquiries all the more worthwhile.
- 调查?  - 什么调查?
-Inquiries? -What inquiries?
趁你还没沉浸在比赛新闻里
Come, Hastings, before you become buried
行动起来 黑斯廷斯
in the pages of the racing.
我不明白为什么你要把时间
I can't see why you want to waste your time
浪费在这种小事上
on such a trivial matter.
黑斯廷斯 你真出乎我的预料
Hastings, you do surprise me.
詹姆斯·卡格尼 (1899-1986): 美国演员
以其在歌舞片 喜剧片 和警匪片中多才多艺的表演而著称
我很清楚这样的小案子
I am well aware that this modest case
和卡格尼先生的电影《执法铁汉》
has not the same dramatic appeal
比起来没有那么激动人心
as the dealings of M. Cagney and his G-men.
即使如此 这个谜团仍值得我们注意
Even so, it is a mystery and worthy of our attention.
啊
Ah.
谢谢
Thank you.
所以这个婆娘自以为
So this dame thinks
她在冲着传来的球跑去
she's heading for the hand-off.
伯特
Burt
美国联邦调查局警探
但她想不到的是
What she ain't thinking is,
这场球赛是联邦警探伯特的主场
Federal Agent Burt is playing for the home team.
四分卫: 美式橄榄球中的一个战术位置 是整个进攻体系的核心
有了联邦调查局担任四分卫
And with the FBI quarterbacking
又有你们伦敦警察厅一路干扰
and you guys from Scotland Yard running interference,
她都跑不出五码远 更别说触地得分了 是不?
she ain't gonna make 5 yards, never mind a touchdown, right?
- 触地得分?  - 对
-Touchdown? -Right.
让我们行动起来
Let's move our butts.
先散了吧 小伙子们 我们中午再集中
All right, lads. We'll reassemble at midday.
波洛 这位是联邦警探伯特
Poirot, this is Federal Agent Burt.
请允许我介绍赫尔克里·波洛
May I introduce Hercule Poirot,
著名的私家侦探
the private detective,
以及他的助手 黑斯廷斯上尉
and his associate, Captain Hastings.
美国犯罪终结者 对吧?
The American crime buster, huh?
贾普 你应该不至于这么缺人手吧
Japp, I hope you're not so short of manpower,
居然沦落到雇佣私家侦探
you're hiring a shamus.
他们擅长做什么? 寻找走丢的小狗?
What are they good for? Chasing lost dogs.
我们要解决的问题
This is a matter of international security
事关国际安全
we're dealing with here.
伯特 我无意雇佣任何人
I have no intention of hiring anyone, Burt.
但你应该知道
And if you must know,
波洛先生在业内声名赫赫
Mr. Poirot here has an outstanding reputation.
唷 卓越不凡的侦探
Oh. A gumshoe of distinction.
阿尔·卡彭 (1899-1947): 美国著名歹徒
1925~1931年为芝加哥犯罪集团首脑
那我想阿尔·卡彭都能竞选总统了
And I suppose Al Capone's running for president.
喂 讲
Yeah. Yeah?
好好好 那又怎样?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. So what?
好 继续努力
All right. So keep trying.
哦 你听说了什么?
Oh, you heard what?
听着 伙计 别跟我提什么狗屁兄弟会
Listen, pal, don't give me this Brotherhood garbage,
这完全是捕风捉影 明白吗?
'cause it's all smoke, you understand?
这种横跨大西洋的合作
This, uh, liaison transatlantique
想必没有达到预期的效果吧?
does not live up to its expectations?
用术语讲 这根本就是场灾难
Basically, to use a technical term, it's a disaster.
他接管了我的办公室 我的秘书 乃至我的车
He's taken over my office, my secretary, and my car.
还想让我的精兵强将去全天候监视意大利使馆
Now he wants my best men to stake out the Italian Embassy.
全天候监视?
Stake out?
24小时不间断地秘密监视
Clandestine surveillance 'round-the-clock.
万一被伦敦的犯罪分子们发现
If the London underworld find out
我一半的人手都被牵制住了 天都该塌了
that half my division are tied down, they'll have a field day.
的确 但为什么要全天候监视?
Quite so. But why this need for surveillance?
半年前 一个小职员偷了一套
Six months ago, a minor clerk stole the blueprints
美国海军新型潜艇的设计图
for a new submarine from the U.S. Admiralty.
如果落入敌对势力手中
There could be serious consequences
后果将非常严重
if they fall into the wrong hands.
可以说是大祸临头
It could be a catastrophe.
墨索里尼唯独缺少一支强大的海军
The one thing Il Duce lacks is a strong navy.
完全正确
Exactly.
显然 一旦有了五六艘这样的潜艇
And, apparently, with half a dozen of these submarines,
他就足以控制地中海
he could control the Mediterranean.
联邦调查局发现图纸落到了一个女人手里
The FBI's found out that a woman's got the blueprints,
她已经到了伦敦 打算出售这些图纸
and she's come to London to sell them.
啊 现在我记起来了
Aha. Now I remember.
不就是那起"罗梅罗案件"吗?
Was it not the Romero affair?
那个敢于出卖黑手党的魅力四射的女士 是吧?
La femme fatale who dared to double-cross the Mafia, huh?
从某种程度上说 她就是只金丝雀
Was she not at some point in her career a canary?
- 金丝雀?  - 是的 没错
-A canary? -Yes. That's right.
一个歌舞团的歌手
A dance-band singer.
伯特先生称之为"歌舞名媛"
What Mr. Burt calls a "chantoozie."
太粗俗了
Good grief.
真的 黑斯廷斯你得好好补补
Really, Hastings, you must try to keep up
这些时髦的新词了
with the modern idioms, huh?
她现在在伦敦?
And she is here now?
吉姆 请到我办公室来一下
Jim, step into my office for a minute, please.
我跟奥布莱恩打过招呼了
I've had a word with O'Brien.
他会在档案室等你过去
He's expecting you down in the records office.
让您久等了 先生 档案里只查到几个罗宾逊
Sorry about the delay, sir. There's a few Robinsons on file.
这几个罗宾逊 一个是生活放纵的酒鬼
The Robinsons we've got are a drunk and disorderly,
一个袭击过牧师
an assault on a member of the clergy,
奥布莱恩
O'Brien
档案管理员
还有一个为蓄意破坏铁路
and a throwing stones
往铁轨上投掷石块
with intent to do damage to the railway.
没有斯特拉或者詹姆士·罗宾逊的记录
Nothing on a Stella or James Robinson.
你看 他们是一对善良无辜的夫妇
You see? They're just a nice, innocent couple.
过去这六个月里
During the last six months,
您能回忆起哪些未侦破的案子
can you recall any crime as yet unsolved
而主犯可能是年轻夫妇的?
where the chief suspects might be a young couple?
一下子想不起来 先生
Nothing comes to mind immediately, sir.
邦妮和克莱德: 美国强盗小集团 因报界炒作而声名狼藉
1934年被警察设伏击毙
邦妮和克莱德算是一对
There's that Bonnie and Clyde, of course.
但他们还在逃 在美国中西部的某个地方
But they're at large somewhere in the American Midwest.
让我们祈祷他们还在那儿
And let us hope that is where they remain.
罗宾逊夫妇是帕克的朋友
But they're friends of Parker's.
我从小就认识帕克了
I've known Parker since we were at school.
他不会交不法分子做朋友的
He doesn't have friends who are criminals.
- 啊  - 波洛先生?
-Ah. -Uh, M. Poirot?
保罗
Paul
房产经纪人
- 啊 保罗先生 早上好  - 早上好
-Ah, M. Paul. Good morning. -Good morning.
这位是我的助手 黑斯廷斯上尉
This is my associate, Captain Hastings.
早上好
Good morning.
- 我们能进去吗?  - 谢谢
-Shall we go in? -Thank you.
这幢楼很气派吧?
Magnificent facade, isn't it?
是的 的确
Yes, indeed.
我在伦敦见到过的最好的公寓之一
One of the finest I have seen in London.
保罗先生 这幢楼里的户型
M. Paul, are all the apartments in this block
是不是每一户都一样?
of the same layout?
是的 侦探先生
Yes, Detective.
这间是起居室
This is the sitting room.
是按照最高标准精心设计的
It's been designed to the highest standard.
您看这儿 是最新款的内置式电热炉
Here, for example, is the latest in inset electric fires.
整个镶进了墙里 有一挡和两挡可供调节
Fully built in and with a one- or two-bar option.
看上去很雅致 不是吗?
It's very tasteful. Don't you think?
是的 没错
Yes, indeed.
波洛 你光靠看一间空着的公寓是没法
Poirot, you're not gonna learn any more about the Robinsons
进一步了解罗宾逊夫妇的
by looking 'round an empty flat.
黑斯廷斯 在下结论前
Hastings, it is always wise to make a thorough inspection
详细调查总是明智的
before arriving at the final decision.
我不明白
I don't follow you.
黑斯廷斯 我突然想
Hastings, I have the sudden desire
在坎普登山门公寓租套房子
to take an apartment in Campden Hill Gate.
就要这套
This apartment.
厨房配备也是当下最时髦的
The kitchen has been equipped with the most modern appliances.
每一个架子和橱柜都是恰到好处的
Every shelf and cupboard has been discreetly fitted
哪怕是最挑剔的厨师
to provide an environment
也会爱上这个烹饪环境
delightful to even the most particular of cooks.
保罗先生 告诉我
M. Paul, tell me --
这个小门是做什么用的?
For what purpose is this little doorway?
门后面是放垃圾桶的
It's for the dustbins.
每周两次 有专人从楼梯井收走垃圾
They're collected twice weekly from the back stairwell.
啊
Ah.
看得出建筑设计师
It would appear that the architects
为使用便利 考虑得很周到
have thought of every convenience.
你们可以慢慢看
Why don't you examine the place at your leisure?
- 我在楼下等你们  - 您真好
-I'll wait for you downstairs. -You are most kind.
不客气 慢慢看
Not at all. Take your time.
波洛 价格不菲啊
Think of the expense, Poirot.
1基尼合21先令 即1.05英镑
一周要六基尼呢
Six guineas a week.
花在探索惊天阴谋上
Ah, but that is a small cost, Hastings,
这只是比小开销 黑斯廷斯
to pursue the mystery of great intrigue.
阴谋?
Intrigue?
事实的结果可能非常简单
It'll probably turn out to be something perfectly simple.
不过是偏心的女房东被新婚无房的
Eccentric landlady moved to benevolence
小夫妻感动得大发善心罢了
by plight of homeless newlyweds.
黑斯廷斯 但这并不能解释
But this does not explain, Hastings,
为什么楼下那套便宜的公寓
why the cheap flat below this
招租了那么久却一直没有租出去
had been advertised for so long and nobody took it.
也许大家都发现了不对劲的地方吧
Well, perhaps they all found something wrong with it.
而罗宾逊夫妇没有发现?
And the Robinsons did not?
在你看来 他们是容易上当受骗的年轻夫妇吗?
Did they strike you as being the gullible young couple, Hastings?
不 他们不像
No, they didn't.
那么我们可以认为他们拥有一种
So we may assume that they possessed a special quality
其他人所缺少的特殊本领吗?
that the others were lacking, no?
他们不过是对普通夫妇罢了
They're just an ordinary couple.
这就对了 阴谋就在这儿
Voilà. There lies the intrigue.
- 您好 先生  - 谢谢
-Good day, sir. -Thank you.
那么 你们觉得怎么样?
Well, what do you think?
保罗先生 我想这套公寓
M. Paul, I think that the apartment
正是我想要的
is exactly what I want,
我马上就想把它租下来
and I will take possession immediately.
您做了一个聪明的决定
You made a wise decision.
这里的房子可抢手了 不会招租太久的
These flats won't be on the market for very long,
根据现在的行情 租金也非常合理
and the rent is very reasonable by today's standard.
出租车
Taxi!
是的 但不如罗宾逊夫妇那套便宜
Yes, but not as reasonable as that of the Robinsons'.
- 哦 您认识罗宾逊夫妇?  - 是的 认识
-Oh, you know the Robinsons? -Oh, yes, indeed.
他们刚搬进去没多久
In fact, they have just moved in.
不是吗?
Is that not so?
罗宾逊夫妇? 住在6室的那对?
The Robinsons? In number 6?
他们半年前就搬进去了
They moved in six months ago.
那天晚上的聚会真是精彩
Splendid party the other night.
很高兴你喜欢 老伙计
Glad you enjoyed it, old boy.
那对罗宾逊夫妇看起来很讨人喜欢
Those Robinsons seemed very pleasant.
那个罗宾逊先生是做什么的 你知道吗?
What does he do? Do you know? Mr. Robinson?
做什么的? 我也不太清楚 他刚来这地方不久
Do? I'm not sure. Hasn't been in town long.
不过看得出是个老实人
Salt of the earth, though.
他们从哪来的?
Where are they from?
不太清楚 应该不是本地人
I don't know. Out of town somewhere.
你是怎么认识他们夫妻俩的呢?
So, how do you know them, then?
事实上 我们是碰巧认识的
Well, that was a bit odd, as a matter of fact.
- 是吗?  - 是的
-Yes? -Yes.
有一次 我和维罗妮卡在剧院看戏
Veronica and I were at the theater,
幕间休息时 我们点了两杯饮料
and we'd ordered some drinks for the interval.
去取的时候 发现有人在喝我们点的饮料
And when we got there, there were these people drinking them.
- 真的?  - 千真万确
-Really? -Absolutely.
似乎我们点的东西是一样的
Well, it seems we'd ordered the same drinks.
我们单子上写的是6号 他们的是9号
Our little chitty said number 6, and theirs was number 9,
仅仅是看颠倒了
only it was upside down.
大家都尴尬了好一会儿
Dashed awkward for a moment there.
明白了
I see.
黑斯廷斯 你迟到了
Hastings, you're late.
我和看门人争执了一会
I had a bit of a run-in with the doorman.
他看上去不想让我进楼
Thought he wasn't gonna let me into the building.
是吗?
Really?
听他说有个外国人一直在楼外面徘徊
Well, it seems there's been some foreign fellow hanging around
询问有关罗宾逊夫妇的事情
asking questions about the Robinsons.
他说的不会是你吧?
Wasn't you, was it?
当然不是我
Certainly not.
很可能是那个一直在监视这幢公寓的男的
It is probably the man who has been watching the flats.
监视这幢公寓?
Watching the flats?
也许罗宾逊夫妇不像看上去那么无辜
Maybe they're not as innocent as they seem.
也许他们身陷某种见不得人的进出口生意之中?
Suppose they're tied up in some shady import-export business?
毒品交易 贩卖人口之类的
Drugs. White slavery.
黑斯廷斯 你想象力真丰富
Hastings, you have the most fertile imagination.
好像没人知道罗宾逊夫妇是从哪来的
Well, nobody seems to know where the Robinsons have come from.
帕克对他们一无所知
Parker doesn't know anything about them at all.
也许他们刚回国
Perhaps they've just returned from abroad.
如果真是这样 黑斯廷斯
If this is true, Hastings,
你很快就有机会求证的
you will soon have the opportunity to find out.
但现在 我们得开始干活了
But now, please, we must begin our work.
还有 黑斯廷斯 请拿上我的手提箱
Oh, and, Hastings, please bring my valise.
好的
Right.
现在 黑斯廷斯 我准备要进入
Now, Hastings, I am about to enter
罗宾逊家的公寓了 就从运垃圾的小门进去
the flat of the Robinsons after the method of the dustbins.
你要闯入他们家?
You're going to break into their flat?
不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no.
确切地说不是闯入 我的朋友
Not break in, precisely, mon ami.
而是为后面的事情准备准备
But I have to provide for later.
但现在是周六下午 波洛
But, Poirot, it's Saturday afternoon.
他们肯定在家
They're bound to be at home.
那正是我希望的 我的朋友
That is exactly what I'm hoping, mon ami,
因为你恰好需要扮演
because you are about to play the role
刚好路过他们家的
of the friendly neighbor
友好邻居的角色
who just happens to be passing by.
我要你拖住这对年轻夫妻
I want you to keep the young couple occupied
以便我做我的工作
while I perform my task.
等他们出门再做不是更容易些吗?
Wouldn't it be easier to wait until they go out?
黑斯廷斯 这一点我已经考虑过了
Hastings, these are things I have already considered.
他们出门的话 那扇小门肯定会被锁上的
While they are out, the doorway, it is always locked.
- 可我该说些什么呢?  - 哼
-What am I gonna say? -Hmm.
黑斯廷斯上尉 快请进来
Captain Hastings. Do come in.
啊 黑斯廷斯
Oh. Hastings.
什么风把你给吹来了?
What brings you to this neck of the woods?
要我猜
If you ask me,
是私人侦探天生的好奇心
the natural curiosity of the private investigator
促使了这次来访
has prompted this visit.
不 完全不是
No, not at all.
事实上 我要去布朗普顿路办点事
In fact, I had some business to attend to in the Brompton Road.
正巧我想起来你们就住在附近
And when I remembered you were living nearby,
我突然有个念头 "罗宾逊夫妇 当然了
I suddenly thought, "The Robinsons. Of course.
"他们肯定知道"
They're bound to know."
你们说说 我是用獾毛
Now, should I use badger hair,
还是用一把普通的刷子就成?
or will an ordinary brush do the trick?
你说什么?
I'm sorry?
我想要的是一种颗粒感
Well, what I want is a sort of impression of graininess
但又不要太明显
without it being too obvious.
我不想要看起来坑坑洼洼的
I don't want it to look ridgy.
有些人确实喜欢弄得坑坑洼洼的 不是吗?
I mean, it sometimes does look ridgy, doesn't it?
我坚决不要那样子
I'm dead set against that.
你们看 有这样几种选择
You see, you've got the choice --
马毛 猪鬃 或是獾毛
horsehair, hog bristle, or badger hair.
当然 一把齿很细的钢梳也能做到同样的效果
And, apparently, a fine steel comb produces the same effect,
只是它一般用在墙和地板上
only it's better on walls and floors.
轮廓更明显
More defined.
黑斯廷斯上尉 你说的这些
Captain Hastings, what would one be doing
獾毛或是钢梳子是做什么用?
with badger hair and a steel comb?
哦 我没说过吗?
Oh, didn't I say?
用来刷家具
Dragging and combing.
你知道它用在木头家具上效果非常好
You know what a fine effect it creates on woodwork.
只是装修这方面 我真算不上是个能手
Only I'm not exactly a dab hand when it comes to decorating,
所以我想 我应该来问问你们的专业意见
so I thought I'd call on you for an expert opinion.
我唯一一次这方面的经验还是在法国
The only time I ever did anything like this
给防空壕刷防腐用的杂酚油的时候
was when I creosoted the dugout in France --
不像你们 看你们装修得多好
not like you, with all the work you've done.
黑斯廷斯 我们什么也没做
Hastings, we haven't done a thing.
我们昨天才搬进来
We only moved in yesterday.
而且 我得承认
And, uh, I have to admit,
我连獾毛刷子是什么样
I wouldn't know a badger-hair brush
见都没见过
from a bucket of beef stew.
啊 你太谦虚了
Oh, you're too modest.
我确定你们在意大利时
I'm sure you were both influenced
都受了文艺复兴文化的影响
by the spirit of the Renaissance during your time in Italy.
意大利?
Italy?
你是怎么有的这种印象啊?
Whatever gave you that idea?
帕克不是说你们刚从欧洲大陆回来吗?
Didn't Parker say you'd just returned from the Continent?
不
No.
我们是从剑桥来的
We came down from Cambridge
伦敦协助信用合作社给詹姆士提供了一个职位
when James was offered a position at London Mutual.
我们从没去过欧洲大陆
We've never been on the Continent.
保险
Insurance.
这是一个不错的话题
Now, that is an interesting subject.
事实上 我一直在考虑买个新的保险
In fact, I've been thinking about taking out a new policy.
究竟是什么声音?
What on earth was that?
厨房传过来的
It came from the kitchen.
- 我什么都没听到  - 我最好去看看
-I didn't hear anything. -I'd better take a look.
让我去吧
Allow me.
侦探的优先权
Detective's prerogative.
谁知道呢 说不定是个鬼魂呢
You never know. It might be one of the ghosts.
我猜是风把它吹开的
Wind blew it open, I expect.
我是你们的话 就会把这个门一直闩好
I should keep this bolted if I were you.
谁知道这附近有些什么人啊
You never know who's about.
要是被罗宾逊夫妇看到波洛
I don't know what the Robinsons would have said
消失在昏暗的楼梯井里的身影
if they'd seen the foot of Hercule Poirot
真不知道他们会说什么
disappearing into the twilight of the back stairwell.
我很感谢你敏捷的反应 我的朋友
I am indebted to your quick thinking, mon ami.
弗洛伦斯·南丁格尔 (1820-1910): 英国护士学先驱 妇女护士职业创始人
那所房子就是以前弗洛伦斯·南丁格尔...
And that house is where Florence Nightingale...
我不信罗宾逊夫妇有什么好隐藏的
I can't believe the Robinsons have anything to hide.
如果非说有人行事可疑的话
If anyone's behaving in a suspicious manner,
也是那个把房子租给他们的女人
it's that woman who let the flat to them.
但是你不觉得奇怪吗 我的朋友?
But did it not strike you as odd, mon ami,
房产经纪人关于罗宾逊太太的描述
that the estate agent's description of Mme. Robinson
跟我们认识的这个罗宾逊太太很不一样
was so very different from the Mme. Robinson that we know?
那人不善于观察呗
Not the most observant of fellows.
可能是不同的两个罗宾逊太太吧
Perhaps they are different Mme. Robinsons, huh?
也许他说的那个罗宾逊太太等了很久
Perhaps his Mme. Robinson had been waiting a long time
才找到了相同姓氏的租客
to find a subtenant of the same name.
她到底为什么要那么做呢?
Why on earth would she do that?
真奇怪
That's strange.
那个园丁长得和贾普的手下
That gardener's a dead ringer
达特依巡佐简直一模一样
for Japp's man Sergeant Daltry.
嗯 你的眼睛没骗你 我的朋友
Hmm. Your eyes, they do not deceive you, mon ami.
到这儿来
Come here.
如果我没弄错的话
If I am not mistaken,
这辆货车就是贾普总督察全天候监视
this van is the nerve center of Inspector Japp's stakeout
意大利使馆的指挥部
at the Italian Embassy.
你们俩在这儿干嘛?
What are you two doing here?
我们俩刚好路过
Well, it happens that we were passing by,
还有 我不得不满足
and, uh, well, it is necessary
黑斯廷斯的好奇心
to satisfy the curiosity of Hastings.
波洛
Poirot.
趁没人看见你们 赶快进来吧
You better come inside before somebody sees you.
您看 前前后后每个出入口都被覆盖到了
So, look, all the exits are covered, front and back,
而且还有两辆不起眼的车子随时待命
and we have a couple of unmarked cars just standing by
万一她决定要带着图纸潜逃
in case she decides to take it on the lam.
无论怎样 只要卡拉·罗梅罗一出现
Whichever way, as soon as Carla Romero shows up,
随时准备逮捕她
we're ready to nab her.
真是策划得天衣无缝 伯特先生
A well-staged operation, Mr. Burt.
很高兴我能帮上忙
Glad I could be of some help.
那个男的是谁?
Who is that man?
他一直进进出出
Oh, he's in and out all the time.
我猜是个遇到了麻烦的游客
Some tourist in trouble, I guess.
假如卡拉·罗梅罗一直不出现
Suppose Carla Romero never comes, huh?
假如她叫别的人来呢?
Suppose she sends someone else?
好吧
All right.
作为一个私家侦探 您会怎么做?
As a private dick, what would you do, huh?
径直走进去 要求他们在拿到图纸后
Just walk right in there and ask them to call us
给我们打电话吗?
when the blueprints show up?
我会集中精力找出这个卡拉·罗梅罗
I would concentrate my efforts on trying to find Carla Romero.
她是个年轻惹眼的美国人
She is a young, attractive American.
独自一人旅行
And traveling alone,
一定是个非常引人注意的人物
she would be a figure most conspicuous.
也许不是独自
Alone she might.
我们知道有个同犯跟她一起旅行
But we know she's traveling with an accomplice.
伯特先生 我知道
M. Burt, I understand
她跟黑手党打过交道
that she has had some dealings with the Mafia.
你们什么时候才能明白?
When will you guys understand
这案子根本扯不上什么黑手党
there is no such thing as the Mafia
黑帮歹徒 或是地下犯罪组织
or the Black Hand or the Cosa Nostra?
确实 有一些移民家庭
Sure, there's some immigrant families
一些来自欧洲南部的人
of mainly Southern European extraction
彼此之间总是过不去
who push each other around.
但是有组织的犯罪 不 先生
But organized crime -- No, sir.
不用
No.
不 谢谢 但是...
No, thank you, but...
是的 我肯定她是的
Yes, I'm sure that she is.
是的 但是您看 我没兴趣
Yes, but you see, that is of no interest.
不 一点兴趣也没有
No. No interest at all.
完全没有 但还是谢谢
None whatsoever. But thank you.
好的 再见
Yes. Goodbye.
黑斯廷斯 我给十四家夜总会打了电话
Hastings, I've telephoned 14 nightclubs.
其中有八家有歌舞名媛
Eight of them have the chantoozies,
但没有一个是美国人
but none of them American.
三家有男歌手
Three of them have the male crooners,
一家有魔术师 还有一家有钢琴师
one of them has a magician, one, a pianist.
还有一家黑猫夜总会一直没人接电话
And the Black Cat won't answer the telephone.
你在找什么?
And what are you looking for?
假设 黑斯廷斯
Suppose, Hastings,
卡拉·罗梅罗被迫回去干老本行
that Carla Romero is forced to return to her old trade
挣钱糊口 同时伺机卖掉那些图纸
to support her while she is waiting to sell those documents.
那倒是有可能
Well, it's possible, I suppose.
为什么你突然对卡拉·罗梅罗这么感兴趣?
Why are you so interested in Carla Romero all of a sudden?
为什么不让联邦调查局自己破自己的案子?
Why not let the FBI solve their own cases?
因为这案子可能牵涉到罗宾逊夫妇
But there is a connection, perhaps, with the Robinsons.
那个被我看见走进意大利使馆的男的
The man that I saw entering the Italian Embassy
跟在罗宾逊夫妇公寓外监视的 是同一个人
is the same man who has been watching their apartment.
都好了
All right there!
你不觉得这很让人好奇吗 黑斯廷斯?
And do you not find it intriguing, Hastings,
唯一不接电话的那家夜总会
that the only club who did not answer the telephone
偏偏名叫"黑猫"
was the Black Cat?
今晚
献唱
埃尔莎
哈特
得了多少钱?
How much you got?
12英镑
£12?
剩下的钱呢?
Where's the rest of it?
没有了
No.
埃尔莎·哈特
下午好
Good afternoon.
请问 麻烦您告诉我 你们的经理在吗?
I wonder, could you tell me, please, is the manager here?
后面
Back there.
谢谢 您人真好
Thank you. Most kind.
经理室
嗯 嗯
Uh -- Uh...
等一下 谁在门口?
Just a minute. Who is it?
赫尔克里·波洛
Hercule Poirot.
- 再说一遍  - 波洛
-Come again? -Poirot.
伯尼·科尔
Bernie Cole
黑猫夜总会老板
那么您是?
And you?
没什么好隐瞒的 伯尼·科尔
I've got nothing to hide. Bernie Cole.
- 进来说吧  - 谢谢
-Come in. -Thank you.
大家都认得我 伯尼·科尔 夜总会之王
Everyone knows me, anyway. Bernie Cole, King of the Clubs.
您以前没有常常光顾老卡普里斯吗?
Didn't you used to come down to the old Caprice?
没有
No.
那样的话 您到底想找什么?
What are you after, then, anyway?
没什么非法的吧? 我猜
Nothing illicit, I trust?
没 当然没有
No. Certainly not.
哦
Oh.
请原谅 先生 那一直在响的不是电话吗?
Pardon, monsieur, but is that not a telephone under there?
不
No.
好吧 是
Well, yes.
烦死人了 是吧?
Drives you mad, doesn't it?
- 伯尼·科尔?  - 某个人
-Bernie Cole? -Some people.
先生 埃尔莎·哈特小姐在这儿唱歌 是吧?
Monsieur, Mlle. Elsa Hart is singing here, is she not?
是谁想知道?
Who wants to know?
外面有张海报
There is a poster outside.
我想问 是那个美国人埃尔莎·哈特吗?
What I want to know is, is it Elsa Hart the American?
不是
No.
啊
Ah.
我在纽约听过一次她唱的歌 您知道
I heard her in New York once, you understand.
是吗? 她是加拿大人
Oh, yes? Well, she's Canadian.
迪翁五胞胎: 在医学和遗传学记录中首例存活下来的五胞胎
1934年生于加拿大安大略省 自幼便成为国际知名人物
跟迪翁五胞胎一样
Like those Dionne quintuplets.
很快就会流行起来的 加拿大
It's gonna be all the rage soon -- Canada.
我们会有加拿大的这个 加拿大的那个
We'll have Canadian this, Canadian that.
伯尼·科尔总是能够抓住流行趋势
Bernie Cole can always spot a trend.
并以此闻名
Known for it.
我知道你能听到
I know you're there!
但如果那个经理说她是加拿大人
But if the manager says she's Canadian...
她当然会那么告诉经理 黑斯廷斯
But of course she would tell him that, Hastings.
她偷了图纸 她的仇人在找她
She has stolen the blueprints. Her enemies are pursuing her.
她改了名字 干嘛不改国籍呢?
She changes her name. Why not also her nationality?
对啊 我想也是
Yes, I suppose so.
然后 尽管那样小心防备
Then, in spite of all her precautions,
她发现还是有人找到她了
she discovers that someone has tracked her down.
所以她决定离开自己的公寓
So she decides to leave her own apartment
并且让相同姓氏的人住进去
and to install someone of the same name.
罗宾逊夫妇
The Robinsons?
什么? 你的意思是女房东利用他们做诱饵?
What, you mean the landlady's using them as a decoy?
是的 我的朋友
Yes, mon ami.
慷慨的女房东 偷图纸的狡猾间谍
The charitable landlady, the devious agent of espionage,
也许还有歌手埃尔莎·哈特
and perhaps also the singer Elsa Hart
肯定都是同一个人
are surely one and the same.
我觉得我的想象力够丰富的了
I thought I was the one with the fertile imagination.
这太不可思议了
This is fantastic.
不 黑斯廷斯
No, Hastings.
这是个用心险恶的阴谋
This is a plot of sinister dimensions.
罗宾逊夫妇会成为一场残忍暗杀的刀下鬼
The Robinsons are to be the victims of a ruthless assassin.
晚上好
Good evening.
我是《女性知音》杂志社的佩内洛普·梅特兰
Penelope Maitland from "The Lady's Companion."
我早先送过便条来的
I sent a note 'round earlier.
哦 是的 欢迎欢迎
Ah, yes. Very nice, too.
请进
Please come in.
您为什么从来不接电话?
Why do you never answer your telephone?
这年头骚扰电话实在太多了 不是吗?
You get all these nuisance calls these days, don't you?
善意地提醒一下 亲爱的
A friendly word of warning, my dear --
她不太喜欢接受采访
She wasn't keen on the idea.
可能会显得比较冷淡
She may seem a bit frosty.
权当艺术家的脾气吧
Put it down to artistic temperament.
做您这一行的 肯定非常擅长
I'm sure you're used to dealing with all sorts of people
跟各式各样的人打交道
in your line of business.
说得太对了
Yes, indeed.
顺着走廊直走 左边第二个门就是
Uh, straight down the corridor. Second on the left.
祝顺利
Good luck.
事后来找我喝一杯
Come and see me afterwards for a drink.
罗梅罗的丈夫
Romero's Husband
埃尔莎·哈特小姐在吗?
Miss Elsa Hart?
卡拉·罗梅罗
Carla Romero
女歌手
有事吗?
Yes?
《女性知音》杂志社的佩内洛普·梅特兰
Penelope Maitland from "The Lady's Companion."
干嘛不进来说呢?
Why don't you come in?
啊 原来您也唱《百老汇摇篮曲》
Oh, I see your repertoire includes "Lullaby of Broadway."
这是我最爱的曲子之一
It's one of my own favorites.
真的吗? 那感情好
Really? Glad you like it.
那么 梅... 特兰小姐
Now, Miss, uh, Maitland...
为什么读者们... 什么杂志来着?
...why would the readers of the, uh...
-《女性知音》 - 好的
-"Lady's Companion." -Right.
为什么有人想要看关于夜总会歌手的文章呢?
Why would anyone want to read about a nightclub singer?
她们是被您的浪漫和魅力所吸引 哈特小姐
It's the glamour and the romance, Miss Hart.
现代女性的典型
The image of the modern woman.
您看 我听说您来英国的时间不长
Now, I understand you've only been in England a short time.
她说她过去这九个月来
So she says she has been touring
一直陪丈夫在欧洲的
the capital cities of Europe with her husband
各首都城市旅行?
for the past nine months?
是的 在各个夜总会上班
Yes. Working in a variety of nightclubs.
嗯
Uh-huh.
可我们勇敢的女记者不相信她的话?
But our intrepid journalist was not convinced, huh?
布洛涅森林: 巴黎西部的森林公园 拿破仑在位期间所建
任何一个声称在布洛涅森林里
Anyone who claims to have been stag hunting
狩猎过雄鹿的人 波洛先生
in the Bois de Boulogne, Mr. Poirot,
都对欧洲大陆的生活存在严重误解
has been seriously misinformed about life on the Continent.
真了不起
Extraordinaire.
还有别的什么吗?
There was something more?
她的更衣室里有本歌谱
There was a song sheet in her dressing room.
是去年一月份在美国出版的
An American publication dating back to last January.
我有非常可靠的消息来源
I have it on good authority
说这本书在美国以外根本买不到
it isn't obtainable outside the United States.
它只在美国出售
It could only have been obtained in America.
莱蒙小姐...
Miss Lemon...
我相信《女性知音》杂志社
I believe that the newest recruit
最新的员工 抢到了头条新闻
of "The Lady's Companion" has made a scoop.
已经过了半夜了
It's gone midnight.
我们要等多久?
How long are we gonna wait?
有必要的话 等到天亮
All night if necessary, mon ami.
我恐怕你没法睡你的美人觉了
I am afraid you may lose your beauty sleep.
我反正也没法儿合眼
I wouldn't get a wink, anyway,
绞尽脑汁搞清楚这起间谍案里到底谁是谁
trying to fathom out who's who in this espionage business.
这是个刁滑的案件
It is a devious affair.
可是罗梅罗起先究竟是怎么
How did Romero manage to steal the documents
搞到图纸的呢?
in the first place?
卡拉·罗梅罗不是个贼 我的朋友 她是个狐狸精
Carla Romero is not a thief, mon ami, but a temptress.
黑斯廷斯 我来详细地给你讲讲这段小历史
Hastings, I will recount to you the little history.
这个故事会让你想起你最爱的电影
It is a story that will remind you of your favorite cinema.
故事开始于六个月前
To begin, we have to go back six months
发生在纽约东城
to the East Side of New York,
人尽皆知的卡拉·罗梅罗小姐
where the notorious Carla Romero was working
在一个夜总会里当歌手
as a singer in a nightclub.
♪ 我会不远万里 ♪
♪ I'll make a million trips ♪
♪ 来到他的唇边 ♪
♪ To his lips ♪
♪ 我愿变成蜜蜂 ♪
♪ If I were a bee ♪
♪ 因它对我来说 ♪
♪ 'Cause they are sweeter than ♪
♪ 甜过任何糖果 ♪
♪ Any candy to me ♪
♪ 他是粒粒砂糖 ♪
♪ He's granulated sugar ♪
♪ 我必忠贞不渝 ♪
♪ I'll never cheat on my sugar ♪
♪ 甜心我的挚爱 ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm too sweet on my sugar ♪
♪ 我的宝贝甜心 ♪
♪ That sugar baby of mine ♪
♪ 我是那么爱你 我的宝贝甜心 ♪
♪ I'm too sweet on that sugar baby of mine ♪
路易·瓦尔达诺
Luigi Valdarno
美国海军部职员
她设法找到并勾引了一个
She had sought out and seduced a young clerk
美国海军部的年轻职员
in the American Department of the Navy.
这个职员名叫路易·瓦尔达诺
His name was Luigi Valdarno.
事情办得如何?
How did it go?
不费吹灰之力
Like taking candy from a baby.
我这就去准备
I'll get ready.
十分钟后在门口见
Meet you out front in 10 minutes.
这个狐狸精把他整个魂都给勾走了
He was so besotted with this siren
说服他从美国海军部
that persuading him to steal the secret papers
偷出秘密图纸简直易如反掌
from the U.S. Navy was an easy task.
可瓦尔达诺想不到的是
Unknown to Valdarno,
在这个狡猾的阴谋里 卡拉·罗梅罗还有个同伙
the accomplice of Carla Romero in this sinister plot
就是她的丈夫
was her husband.
当晚瓦尔达诺载着罗梅罗来到一处废弃的码头
That same night, Valdarno drove Carla Romero to a deserted wharf
他以为罗梅罗在那儿安排了
where he believed she had arranged a rendezvous
与意大利政府特工的会面
with an agent of the Italian government.
这些新型美军潜艇的图纸
The blueprints for the new American submarine
可以交易五十万美元
would be exchanged for half a million dollars.
好了 宝贝 你在这等我一下
This is it, baby. Take it nice and slow.
路易
Luigi.
多亏了你 一切都太简单了
You made it all too easy.
卡拉 不
Carla, no.
永别了 小情人
Goodbye, lover boy.
我们快走
Let's get out of here.
他们原本得到的指示是把这些图纸
Their instructions had been to deliver the blueprints
交给兄弟会的联络人
to the contact in the Brotherhood.
但罗梅罗和她的丈夫打了个小算盘
But Romero and her husband had a better idea.
他们没有把图纸交给在黑手党里的头目
Instead of passing the documents to her masters in the Mafia,
罗梅罗和她丈夫俩横渡大西洋 逃跑了
Carla Romero and her husband fled across the Atlantic
改头换姓为罗宾逊夫妇
under the name of Robinson
想卖掉图纸独吞巨款
to sell the documents for their own gain.
后来 他们发现被黑手党的杀手追上了
Then they discovered they had an assassin on their trail.
是的
Yes.
黑手党上了罗梅罗的当简直怒不可遏
The deception of Carla Romero so infuriated the Mafia
出于自身的荣誉 他们必须复仇
that their code of honor would demand revenge.
嗯
Hmm.
准备好 我的勇士
Prepare yourself, mon brave.
我们的客人到了
Our visitor has arrived.
慢着点 黑斯廷斯
Slowly, Hastings.
我们不能发出任何动静
We must be as quiet as the chapel mouse.
我觉得保险起见该让罗宾逊夫妇出去避一避
I still think it would've been safer to evacuate the Robinsons.
这么做会引起不必要的注意
To do so would have created the unnecessary attention.
如果他们像我想的那样无辜
If they are as innocent as I suspect,
最好还是什么也别让他们知道
it would be better that they know nothing of this.
他正在撬门锁
He's picking the lock on the front door.
黑斯廷斯 把你的手枪给我
Hastings, pass me your revolver.
按计划就位
Take up your position as planned.
黑手党杀手
Mafia Assassin
来吧
Allez!
啊
Aah!
黑斯廷斯 手枪
Hastings, the gun.
啊
Aah!
当心 黑斯廷斯
Be careful, Hastings.
咱们跟上
Let us go.
哪儿都看不到他
Nowhere to be seen.
波洛 这糟透了
Poirot, this is a disaster.
别担心 我的朋友 今晚他不会回来了
Well, do not worry, mon ami. He will not return here tonight.
我们年轻的朋友安全了
Our young friends are safe.
现在 是时候去会会那个
But now it is time to make our acquaintance
很难捉的卡拉·罗梅罗了
with the elusive Carla Romero.
♪ 生活满是生机 ♪
♪ Got my life on the move ♪
♪ 只要有你 ♪
♪ If I had you ♪
黑斯廷斯 波洛
Hastings. Poirot.
总督察 伯特先生
Chief Inspector. M. Burt.
- 好了 咱们上  - 上 伙计们
-All right. Let's go. -Come on, lads.
♪ 我会是个国王 宝贝 尽管没有王冠 ♪
♪ I could be a king, dear, uncrowned ♪
♪ 无论穷困潦倒 ♪
♪ Humble or poor ♪
♪ 还是飞黄腾达 ♪
♪ Rich or renowned ♪
晚上好 波洛先生
Evening, Mr. Poirot.
- 晚上好 科尔先生  - 您来头不小啊
-Good evening, M. Cole. -You're a quiet one.
帮我在总督察面前美言几句 好吗?
Put in a good word for me with the chief inspector, eh?
这您不必担心 科尔先生
Have no fear, M. Cole.
有时候 伯特警官
You see, Agent Burt,
走丢的小狗是远在天边
sometimes a lost dog can be found in a place so conspicuous,
近在眼前
it is the last to be considered.
希望您是对的 波洛
You'd better be right, Poirot,
不然我就得改行找走丢的小狗了 在阿拉斯加
or I'll be the one chasing lost dogs -- in Alaska.
我们可以完全信任
I think we can rely on
波洛先生的灰色小细胞 伯特
Mr. Poirot's little gray cells, Burt.
来一瓶香槟
Bottle of champagne.
她现在唱的是最后一首曲子 总督察
She's performing her last song now, Chief Inspector.
但愿如此 科尔先生
Let's hope so, Mr. Cole.
她一走下舞台
As soon as she leaves the stage,
我要你立刻清场
I want you to clear the building.
包在我身上 长官
You can depend on me, Chief.
是卡拉·玛利亚·罗梅罗 没错就是她
That's Carla Maria Romero, all right.
♪ 航向浩瀚的大海 ♪
♪ Sail the mighty ocean wide ♪
咱们去抓住她
Let's tackle her.
你以为你在做什么?
What do you think you're playing at?
- 什么?  - 你不能举着枪到处跑
-What? -You can't go waving guns about.
- 把枪给我  - 你开玩笑吗?
-Give that to me. -Are you kidding me?
快把它给我 否则这次行动就毁了
You just give that to me, or the whole operation's off.
这真让人难以置信
Nobody's gonna believe this.
什么逻辑
The idea.
收好了 警员
Look after this, Constable.
♪ 什么都愿意 ♪
♪ There's just nothing I couldn't do ♪
♪ 只要有你 ♪
♪ If I had you ♪
♪ 什么都愿意 ♪
♪ There's just nothing I couldn't do ♪
♪ 只要有你 ♪
♪ If I had you ♪
好了
Right.
不 您先请吧
Oh, no, please. After you.
我就站在后面打毛线好了
I'll just stay in the background with my knitting.
什么事?
Yeah?
啊 哈特小姐
Ah. Mlle. Hart.
我就猜到在这儿能找到您
I had hoped to find you here.
先生
Monsieur.
这是歌迷代表团之类的吗?
This a deputation of admirers or something?
啊 某种意义上是的
Ah, well, in a way, yes.
哈特小姐 您真是有副好嗓子
Mlle. Hart, indeed you have a fine voice.
- 能不能办正事? - 别急 别急
-Can we just do this? -All right, all right.
女歌手的生活一定绚丽多姿吧?
And the life of the chanteuse is a glamorous one, eh?
我们难道要一直这么闲聊下去吗?
Are we gonna talk her to death or what?
但是您的真本事 设计行骗
But your real talents, mademoiselle --
却要劳心费神得多 不是吗?
the cunning and deception-- are far more taxing, no?
你们这是想干什么?
What do you think you're doing here?
难不成要开晚会吗?
Is this a party or something?
是的 一场告别晚会 宝贝
Yeah. A farewell party, sweetie.
哈特小姐
Mlle. Hart...
您或许更愿意被叫做卡拉·罗梅罗?
Or do you prefer to be called Carla Romero?
抑或也许是 罗宾逊太太?
Or perhaps even Mme. Robinson?
因为有杀手追杀
With an assassin on your trail,
你们换了另一对罗宾逊夫妇住进公寓
you substituted the other Robinsons into your flat.
您真够聪明的
You have been very clever.
可有一件事我必须搞清楚 太太
But there is one thing I must know, madame.
最先意识到瓦尔达诺
Was it you who first realized
在海军部的价值的人 是您吗?
the value of Valdarno's position at the Department of the Navy?
是的 计划都是我想出来的
Yeah. I had all the big ideas.
他们就只等收钱
They just palmed all the greenbacks.
即便是您这样绝顶聪明的女人
And there could never be a position
也永远不会有一席之地的 身处黑...
for a woman of your ingenuity in the Ma--
对不起
Pardon.
- 身处兄弟会?  - 兄弟会?
-In the Brotherhood? -Brotherhood?
听着 联邦调查局对此事一清二楚
Look, the FBI is unequivocal in this matter.
根本没有什么他妈的兄弟会
There is no such thing as the goddamn Brotherhood!
他们不听我的
They wouldn't listen to me.
啊 是的
Oh, yeah.
所以您干脆决定一不做二不休 对吗?
So you thought you'd just take on the whole world, huh?
好了 你的路已经走到头了 女士
Well, it's the end of the road for you, lady.
干嘛不现在就把图纸交出来?
So why don't you hand over the blueprints now,
这样大家都可以回家了
and we can all go home?
华盛顿方面会很高兴拿回这些图纸的
Washington will be glad to get this back.
好了 走吧
All right. Move it.
还有你
You too.
你以为你杀了路易
You thought you could kill Luigi
出卖黑手党就万事大吉了?
and double-cross the Cosa Nostra.
你大错特错了 小妹妹
Well, you was wrong, sister.
算总账的时候到了
Now, we're gonna settle the score.
啊 这太棒了
Oh, this is good.
除了好人以外 人人手里都有枪
Everybody's got a heater except the good guys.
你们就这么傻站着看我被他打死吗?
You're just gonna stand there and let him shoot me?
那是我的枪 波洛
That's my gun. Poirot!
不不不 我的朋友
No, no, no, mon ami.
我根本没工夫搭理这些所谓的美国黑帮歹徒
I have no time for these so-called mobsters of America.
这种把戏我见得多了
I have seen enough of this charade.
再往前一步 我就要你的命
One-a more move, is good night.
各位晚安 总算结束了
Good night and good riddance.
这是个体面的夜总会
This is a respectable club.
再见 卡拉
Arrivederci, Carla.
黑斯廷斯 你总是不相信你的老朋友
So, Hastings, never will you trust your old friend, huh?
继续走 别停
Keep walking.
先前在罗宾逊夫妇的公寓里
I took the precaution to remove the bullets
为了以防万一 我把子弹都取出来了
while we were in the apartment of the Robinsons'.
你怎么知道他会跟我们来这儿?
How did you know he'd follow us here?
我们离开坎普登山门公寓的时候
Ah, well, when we left Campden Hill Gate,
那个杀手躲在暗处
the assassin was lying in wait.
我故意提到要与卡拉·罗梅罗会面
I mentioned our rendezvous with Carla Romero
好诱使他跟上我们
so that he would be sure to follow.
怎么样? 伯特警官
So, Agent Burt,
这次行动一箭双雕 对吧?
we have killed both the birds with one shot, huh?
啊 而且不费一枪一弹
Ah. And without firing a single shot.
他们根本逃不掉的
It's no way to run a country.
那么您是说这个... 犯罪组织
So, you say this, uh, association of criminals
专门派了个杀手追杀罗梅罗小姐 是吗?
sent a hit man after Miss Romero, eh?
是的 但她却让另一对同名的夫妇
Yes, but she had planned to deceive him
住进自己的公寓做替罪羊
by installing the young couple of the same name
以此骗过杀手
in her old apartment.
那把枪你耍的是什么把戏?
And what about your joke with the gun, Poirot?
好吧 总督察
Ah, well, Inspector,
你和黑斯廷斯上尉都这么喜欢紧张刺激
you and Captain Hastings are so fond of the suspense.
我怎么能忍心不让
How could I resist the temptation
这个诡计多端的案子发展到最高潮呢?
to bring this intriguing case to the most dramatic climax?
啊 波洛先生
Well, Mr. Poirot...
我可彻底地服了您了
I've really got to hand it to you.
您过奖了 先生
You're most kind, monsieur.
我确信 美国政府一定会
And the U.S. government, I'm sure,
奖赏您做出的功劳的
would like to reward you for all your efforts.
美国海军永远对您感激不尽
The navy will always be in your debt.
茶好了
Tea's ready.
在厨房里 你们请吧
In the kitchen, if you don't mind.
您真是太客气了
That's terribly kind of you.
一伙窃贼盯上了整幢楼?
A gang of burglars working the whole building?
太不可思议了
Quite extraordinary.
您能抓到他们吗?
Do you expect to catch them?
很不幸抓不到 太太
Unfortunately not, madam.
这些人都是专业盗窃犯
They were a professional outfit.
行动的时候还有人放哨
They would have had a man on watch.
我们赶到的时候 他们已经跑了
By the time we arrived, they were gone.
感谢上帝 什么东西也没丢
I suppose we should be grateful nothing was stolen.
还应该感谢黑斯廷斯上尉
And we should thank Captain Hastings
高度的警惕性
for his vigilance.
要不是他注意到了
Because if he had not noticed
通往垃圾箱的小门被人动了手脚
that the door for the dustbins had been tampered with...
天哪
I say.
看这个
Look at this.
这可是我所见过的最专业的
Now, there's a real professional's tool
工具了
if ever I saw one.
嗯 要我说的话 落下它真是太粗心了
Mm. And very careless to leave it behind, if you ask me.
也许我该拿去检验一下指纹
Perhaps I should have it checked for fingerprints.
你什么也检验不出来的 总督察
You will find nothing, Chief Inspector.
真正的专业人士 会戴上手套
For the real professional... he wears the gloves.